28.
我第一次遇见耶稣时
When I first met him…
他说我的世界即将变得更广阔
Jesus said that my world was gonna get a whole lot bigger.
我们找到了那个世界
Well, we found that world.
我们找到了彼此
We found each other.
更广阔的世界属于我们
That…"bigger world" is ours by right.
我们所有人为它聚在了一起
That we've come together for it, all of us…
事实不容置疑 那本就该属于我们
it's that much more true … it's ours by right.
（明天）
任何崇尚和平公正的人
Any person who would live in peace and fairness,
愿意找到共同之处的人
who would find common ground…
世界也属于他们
it's their right, too.
蹲下
Down.
但那些巧取豪夺 肆意杀戮 榨取利益
But those who use and take and kill to carve out the world.
并独占世界的人们 我们要终结他们
and make it theirs alone … we end them.
我们不会为此庆祝
We don't…celebrate it.
我们也不会为此羞耻
We don't have shame about it, either.
只有一个人必须死
There's only one person who has to die…
我会亲手杀了他
and I will kill him myself.
我会的
I will.
一定会
但如果是那些人…
But if it's the others…
那些支持他 站在他那边的人
the others who prop him up, stand by his side,
甚至只是视而不见的人
even those who just look the other way …
随他们吧
so be it.
28.
之后 我们继续开拓这个世界
Then… we keep making the world bigger.
齐心协力
Together.
永远团结
Bound forever!
引用莎翁的话 「今天谁和我同生共死
To quote The Bard, "For he today that sheds his blood with me.
谁就是我的兄弟「
shall be my brother."
如果是女人
For she today…
她就是我的姐妹
my sister.
我们练习过了
We've practiced.
练了一遍又一遍
We've been through it over and over again.
我们都知道计划不会止于今早
We all know the plan doesn't end this morning.
我们也许得人心惶惶好多天
That we may have to live in uncertainty for days,
也许更久
maybe more.
我们得信任彼此
That we have to keep our faith in each other.
如果我们坚持下去 凭借我们拥有的一切
If we can hold on to that with everything we have,
未来就是我们的
the future is ours.
世界就是我们的
The world is ours.
《行尸走肉》
我没事 我是说 我有事 但是
Yeah. I-I'm okay. I mean… I'm not, but…
我被枪打过
I've been shot at.
被丢过微波炉
Someone threw a microwave at me.
所以我就说两句我妈妈常说的话
So I-I'm just gonna say something my mom used to say.
希望能有个好结果
and hope for the best here.
「无论你有什么好东西
"Whatever you have of good,
把它们分给旅人「
spend on the traveler."
我妈妈说过 帮助那些旅人
My mom said that … that helping the traveler,
那些无家可归的人 是最重要的
the person without a home … that's everything.
我确信你目睹过不少事 遇到过不少事
I'm sure you've seen things, been through things,
所以你不信任他人
that you don't trust people.
我懂的 真的
I get it. I get it.
我也不相信别人
I don't, either.
我也遇过不少事
I've been through things, too.
我妈妈 她还说过
My mom … she also said that,
「愿我的仁慈胜过我的怒火」
"May my mercy prevail over my wrath."
不全是我妈妈说的
It's not all my mom.
那…那句是《古兰经》里的
That one… That's from the Quran.
也许我不该这么说
Probably shouldn't have said that.
我甚至都不认识你
I don't even know you,
但我…我好几天没吃饭了
but I ha… I haven't eaten in a few days.
你甚至可能是我的幻觉
You might not even be real.
举起手来
Hands up.
听着
Listen.
我走
I'm gone.
没事的
It's cool.
我只是…
I just …
我只是…想讨点食物
I just wanted some … e-even just some food.
我们本来应该在十字路口见的
We were supposed to meet at the intersection.
我是冲他头顶开的枪
I shot over his head.
我只想赶他走
I just wanted him gone.
他说他…
He said that he was …
我听见他说了什么 听见了大部分
I heard what he said. Most of it.
但他可能是他们中的一员
But he could've been one of them.
像是间谍吗
Like a spy?
我是冲他头顶开的枪
I shot above his head.
假如他不是他们中的一员
If he isn't one of them,
我希望他能挺过去
I hope he makes it.
- 不够的 爸爸 - 什么不够
- It's not?gonna be enough, Dad. - Enough what?
希望
Hope.
（哨站 平台/树上 道森高速路二分之一处）
（周边住宅区 雷耶斯街3000号段）
（佩茨工业研究所 博克路/化工厂）
（研究所）
（杂草丛生的路边房子）
30分钟 大家都准备好了
30 minutes. Everyone's ready.
你准备好了吗
Are you?
眼下的处境是由一个人造成的
It's one person who brought it to this.
一个人
One person.
任何事都会有一个人挑头
It always starts with one person.
就像这事
This did.
我们正在这里做的事
What we're doing here now.
这不是为了我
This … This isn't about me.
对 的确不是
Yes. It isn't.
你确保了这点
You made it like that.
过来
Come here.
这就是了结
This is the end of it.
我知道你想和他一起去
I know you wanted to go with him.
我也是
I did, too.
太煎熬了
Everything hurts.
但我会协助你保卫这里
But I'll help you defend this place.
- 协助我 - 对啊
- Help me? - Oh, yeah.
这里就靠你了
This is your show.
好吧
Okay…
走着瞧
You'll see.
瑞克 你想干什么
What are you up to, Rick?
你真以为能打败我们吗
You think?you're gonna take us on?
我看过你
I saw you…
一边求饶
beggin'.
一边哭泣
Crying.
瑞克 你就等着再求饶吧
You're gonna beg again, Rick.
你的儿子死定了
Your … Your boy's gonna die.
（杂草丛生的路边房子 奥斯汀 侦察队）
不
No, no, no!
来的人真多
Sure are a lot of us here.
我掩护你
I got your back.
真的吗 我俩不过刚认识
Really? You just met me.
这里的人都是刚认识
We all just met each other.
你在祈祷吗
Are you praying?
正准备开始
I always meant to start.
总比不祈祷强
Better late than never.
拿着
Here.
护住胸骨
Over your sternum.
不用 我等会儿就和玛姬一起回去
No, I'm going back with Maggie after.
哥们 穿上
Dude. Sternum.
哥们
Duuuuuude.
你真要去吗
You up to this?
我说服了山顶寨抵抗救世军
I got the Hilltop to stand against the Saviors.
我必须在场
I need to be there.
至少打完头阵
At least for the first part.
人们说妊娠中期也可以打仗
They say you can wage war through the second trimester.
从农场那时起我就一直在抗争
I've been fighting since the farm.
已经停不下来了
Can't stop now.
那明天呢
How about tomorrow?
你设想过明天的情形吗
You been thinking about what that looks like?
是的
Yes, I have.
我不知道能不能等得及
I don't know if I can wait for it.
只需再战一场
Just one more fight.
而且我要在场
And I'm gonna be there.
至少打完头阵
At least for the first part.
我听说山顶寨的医生被抓走了
I'm told the Hilltop lost their doctor.
而且是位产科医生 神之国有医生
An obstetrician, no less. We have a doctor in the Kingdom.
是位很有才华的女性 加入我们吧
A woman of talent. Join us.
我们会守好背后的
We'll get ours back.
是的 耶稣
Yes, Jesus.
你们会守好的
Yes, you will.
就像白天一定会战胜黑夜
As sure as the day defeats the night.
从今天开始 我们要重塑这个世界
And on this day, ?we begin to reshape this world.
为了你的子子孙孙
for your child?and the children to come.
所以开始吧
So let's get started.
怎么了
What?
有你是山顶寨的幸运
Hilltop's lucky to have you.
是你教会了我如何成为值得被追随的领袖
You showed me how to be someone worth following.
很好
Good.
此战过后…
After this…
我追随你
I'm following you.
快到了
Here we go.
十…
10…
九…
9…
八…
8…
七…六…
7…6…
五…
5…
四…
4…
三…
3…
二…
2…
一…
1.
该死
Shit.
不 来了
No. There.
很好
Okay.
还算准时
Close enough.
好 走吧
All right, let's go.
准备好了
?Got it?
好了
Yeah.
它们走向了尸道
?It went up towards the herdway.
多派点人 两辆车 十支枪
Go big. 2 cars, 10 guns.
不能出乱子 现在不行
We're not messing around, not now.
走姐妹路 被封锁了
You take the Sister route. It's locked down.
你觉得是他们干的
Do you think it was them?
不
Nah.
估计是以前的老东西
Probably something left over,
可能压在尸体下面
maybe under one of the bodies.
我想要大动静 德怀特
I want some bang bang, Dwighty.
我要听到尖叫 我要尝到血腥
I want some scream scream. I want blood.
或许你会如愿的
Maybe you'll get lucky.
我们有多接近
How close are we?
很近了
Close.
活见鬼了
Well, shit.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我刚在开会
I was in a meeting.
你把闹钟关了
You turned off the alarm.
你一上午不去他们不会有事的
They can manage without you for one morning.
今天大家都旷工
We're all playing hooky.
所有人吗
All of us?
那首歌不是我放的
Hey, I didn't put that song on.
活见鬼了
Well, shit.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我刚在开会
I was in a meeting.
我看见你们把小挡泥板都带来了
I see you got your little mudflaps with you.
我实在觉得我们
So I'm not exactly feelin' a reason.
没什么必要互相开枪
for us to try throwin' lead at each other.
我在乎我的人
I care about my people.
我可不想随便派他们上战场
I don't want to just march them into the line of fire.
就为了证明「我老二比你们大」
because I want play "My dick is bigger than yours."
我确实比你们大
It is.
你我心知肚明
We both know it.
但就算我不是最大的 我也能欣然接受现实
But I'm also comfortable enough to accept the fact if it wasn't.
我肯定不会为了争这鸟事 送我的人去死
I'm certainly not gonna let my people die over that shit…
不像你
…like you're about to.
所以呢 瑞克 我他妈能为你做什么
So, Rick, what the hell can I do for you?
德怀特
Dwight.
你叫西蒙
Your name's Simon.
你是加文
You're Gavin.
还有你
And you…
瑞吉娜
Regina.
- 瑞克 我不得不… - 不
- Rick, ?I'd feel remiss if … - No.
我知道你是谁
I know who you are.
听好了 你们五个
Listen, you five.
里面的救世军们
The Saviors inside.
你们所有人仍有机会活下来
All of you have a chance to survive here.
逃过这一劫
To survive this.
只要投降 你们都能活
You all can live if you surrender.
过了此刻 就无法保证了
Can't guarantee it any time but now.
此时此刻
Right now.
糟糕
Shit.
- 它会引爆吗 - 我去处理
- Could that thing set it off? - I got it.
只要他们投降
So they surrender…
你和你的小小巡逻队就饶他们一命
and you and your little piss patrol doesn't kill them.
听起来真划算啊
That sounds like a good deal!
那我怎么办 瑞克
What about me, Rick?
我跟你说过 两遍了
I told you. Twice.
你知道会发生什么
You know what's going to happen.
我知道
I do.
我知道会发生什么
I do know what's gonna happen.
而你不知道
You don't.
你不知道接下来会变得有多糟
You have no idea the shit that's about to go down.
我问你 瑞克
Let me ask you something, Rick …
你觉得你这次大战人数够吗
Do you think you have the numbers for this fight?
不够
You don't.
西蒙
Simon?
他当然是去了那里
Of course that's where he went.
你对瑞克
What do you have to say.
和小小巡逻队有什么要说 格雷戈里
to the Rick?and the piss patrol, Gregory?
山顶寨支持尼根和救世军
The Hilltop stands?with Negan and the Saviors.
任何山顶寨的居民
Any resident of the Hilltop who takes up arms.
若敢拿起武器
or who supports this ultimatum.
或支持威胁救世堂或救世军
against the Sanctuary or any of the Saviors, for that matter …
本殖民地将不再欢迎他们
they will no longer be welcome in the colony.
还有呢
And?
他们的家人也会被一同驱逐
Their families will be thrown out.
在外面自生自灭
and will be left to fend for themselves.
还有呢
And?
立刻回家吧
Go home now.
趁现在还有家可回
Or you won't have a home to go back to.
你们想做什么就做什么
You do what you need to do.
我在山顶寨只有一堆书和吃龙虾的破围嘴
All I have at the Hilltop are a bunch of books and an old lobster bib.
你们听到他的话了
You heard the man.
回去继续他妈的分拣小麦吧
Go back to separating wheat and shit.
或者鬼晓得你们这些人做什么
or whatever the hell it is you people do.
看起来没人要走 是吧
Doesn't look like anyone's goin', does it?
山顶寨支持…
Hilltop stands with …
山顶寨支持玛姬
The Hilltop stands with Maggie!
我觉得
I feel…
我对你付出了很多心血
like I invested a lot in you,
我真的非常非常失望
and I am very, very disappointed.
看来战事一触即发了 瑞克
Sounds like?shit is goin' down, Rick.
你的几个副手
You "Lieutenants…"
你们可得想好了
you're gonna have to make up your minds.
要不我们先暂停一下…
Maybe we can take a time-out here …
不 必须是现在
No. This has to happen now.
只有这一条路
This is the only way.
你是要逼我倒数吗
You're gonna make me count.
好吧
Okay.
我数
I'm counting.
开始了
It's started.
对 总会走到这一步
Yeah. It was always gonna be that way.
很高兴与你们合作
Pleasure doing business with you.
打败他们
Beat 'em.
我们会的
We will.
小心一点
Be careful.
该死 会很好玩
Shit, this is gonna be fun.
不会的
No, it isn't.
总好过坐以待毙 对吧
It's better than lettin' things be, though, right?
对
Yeah. It is.
现在
Now!
走
Go!
瑞克
Rick!
他逃不了的
He's not going anywhere!
瑞克
Rick!
瑞克 我们得走了
Rick! We have to go!
瑞克
Rick!
瑞克 他跑不掉的
Rick!?He's not going anywhere!
我们得撤了
We have to leave now!
不是为了你 对吗
It's not about you, right?
不是为了你
Not about you.
过来
Come here.
不 等等
No, no. Wait. Wait.
该死
Shit.
我会救你出去的
I'm gonna get you out of here.
我们只需等待时机
We just have to wait for our moment.
谢谢你 神父
Thank you, Father.
谢谢上帝吧
Thank God.
好 随便吧
Sure, whatever.
子弹 离我们很近
The … The … The shots … they're too close!
他们为什么朝我开枪
Why are they firing at me?
等等
Wait.?
等一下
Wait!
等等
（对不起）
我们还能再等会儿
We can wait some more.
等不了了
We can't.
他叫走了我
He stopped to get me.
什么
How's that?
尼根
Negan.
他在地上
He was on the ground.
我试图杀他 加百利叫走了我
I was trying to kill him, and Gabriel stopped to get me.
我们得动身了
We gotta start out.
你没事吧
You all right?
这不是为了我
This isn't about me.
走吧
Let's go.
好
Yeah.
我们本打算用弓箭干掉守卫
We were gonna start with taking out the guards with arrows.
你觉得隔着尸群你还能射中吗
You think you can still hit them through that?
我不是很有把握
I wouldn't bet on it.
趴下
Down!
我希望你穿着拉屎裤
I hope you got your shitting pants on.
什么
What?
拉屎裤
Your shittin' pants.
我希望你现在穿着它
I hope you're wearing them right now…
因为你
…'cause you…
就要拉裤了
are about to shit your pants.
爸爸
Daddy!
- 他们为派对做了个大猫头鹰 - 什么
- They made a big owl for the party! - What?
大家对这个节日极为认真
People are taking this festival extremely seriously.
大猫头鹰
A big owl?
在外面
It's outside.?
它们会抓到你的
They're gonna get you.
永远不会 我们去看看好吗
Never. Should we go see?
我才不怕大猫头鹰
I'm not afraid of a big owl.
有多大
How big is it?
我的仁慈
My mercy…
胜过
prevails…
我的怒火
over my wrath.
我不想再等了
I don't want to wait for it anymore.
你们也不用等 是的 我知道
You don't either … Yeah, I know.
所以我们不用等
So we don't have to wait for it.
如果我们明天就开始
If we start tomorrow right now…
凭着我们战胜的困难
with everything we've beaten,
我们承受的苦难
everything we've endured,
我们度过的难关 我们至今的成长
everything we've risen above, everything we've become…
如果我们明天就开始
If we start tomorrow right now…
不管接下来遇到什么 我们都赢了
no matter what comes next… we've won.
我们已经赢了
We've already won.
纪念约翰·博奈克
纪念乔治·罗梅罗